(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-09T22:10:54.110712",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
【告知あり！】8/8 (土) 20:00 3D新衣装お披露目ミニライブ #常闇トワ生誕祭2026
[Announcement!] 8/8 (Sat) 20:00 3D New Outfit Reveal Mini-Live #TokoyamiTowaBirthdayFestival2026
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
寒い寒い 夜の
In the freezing cold night,
とばり凍る言葉
words freeze in the veil of darkness.
受け流して
Letting them slide by,
彗星を待ってた
I waited for a comet.
光には遠い心で
With a heart so far from the light,
それでも
even so...
輝きへと手を伸ばした​い
I want to reach my hand out towards the radiance.
それには 暴れる夢が痛い
For that, my wild dreams ache.
今は今は名も無き花
Right now, right now, I'm a nameless flower,
以前の蕾だと
still just a bud before blooming.
此の世の嵐を耐えなが​ら描くよ
While enduring the storms of this world, I'll paint it.
情熱は絶やさぬままで
Keeping my passion alive.
泣きそうな時は泣いてし​まえ
When you feel like crying, just cry it out.
それが未来 開花 魁となれ
Let that become the harbinger of a future blooming!
瞳の純度は上がること​になるから
Because the purity of your eyes will only increase,
無駄になんかならない
none of it will ever go to waste.
泣きそうな時は泣いてし​まえ
When you feel like crying, just cry it out.
今日はそんな日もあると​笑って
Smile and say, "Some days are just like that."
涙と混ぜられ、希望よ
Mixed with tears, oh hope,
そんな感じ？
is that how it feels?
華麗に咲き誇る
Blooming magnificently,
前哨戦
this is the prelude!
放ちながら交差した
Unleashing, they crossed paths
擬似化してバイブレーション
Simulating and vibrating
怖がらずに 怯まずに
Without fear, without flinching
負けたくない 枯れたくない
I don't want to lose, I don't want to wither
1、2、3!
1, 2, 3!
一つじゃない
There isn't just one...
いくつも
...there are many...
願い叶えたい
...wishes I want to make come true.
たどり着ける
I will be able to reach...
やっとの彗星
...that comet at last.
叫びへと変わる祈り
A prayer that turns into a scream
それなら届きそうだ
If so, it feels like it will reach
掴んでみせてそれから
Show me you can grasp it, and then
散らない夢を見よう
let's dream a dream that never fades
されどされど名も無き
And yet, and yet, nameless
花の胸の誇りは
The pride in the flower's heart
冬の何より尊いと思うよ
I believe is more precious than anything in winter
誰も 誰も 洒落っ気なくても
Even if no one, absolutely no one is fancy
我思うゆえにの自分
I am myself because I think
泣いちゃった分だけ僕よ逞しく
As much as I cried, make me stronger
もっともっとってよくばりかい
Is it greedy of me to want more and more?
よくばりじゃない 願いだ 願いだ
It's not greed, it's a wish, it's a wish
命の強さを 色づけて
Coloring the strength of life
泣いちゃった分だけ僕よ逞しく
As much as I cried, make me stronger
夕闇に 咲きゆくとなれ
Become one that blooms in the twilight
うつせみ浮き世を さあ 忍びの歩に乗って
Riding on stealthy steps through this fleeting world
うるわしく咲かせよう この心
Let's make this heart bloom beautifully
泣きそうな時は泣いてしまえ それが未来
When you feel like crying, just cry, that is the future
咲き誇れ 咲きゆくとなれ
Bloom proudly, become one that blooms
瞳の温度は上がり続けるよ
The temperature of my eyes keeps rising
咲き誇れ もうちょっと
Bloom proudly, just a bit more
うるわしく咲かせよう この心
Let's make this heart bloom beautifully
Thank you!
浴びるほど聞いて 本当の言葉を
Listen until you're drenched, to the real words
息づく鼓動を
to the breathing heartbeat.
生きているのならただ消えぬように
If you are alive, just so as not to fade away,
まだ息をしたい 理由があるの
I still want to breathe, there is a reason.
不可視
[Song: Fukashi / Lyrics & Music: Yuriikaon]
幸せだけを選んでいたって
Even if I only chose happiness,
先は見えない
I wouldn't see the future.
過ぎ去った今を
Saying there is nothing to be done
仕方ないなんて消せればいいけど
about the past now, if only I could erase it, but...
嘘で
With lies...
また惑わされる夢じゃない
...it's not a dream where I can be deluded again.
浴びるほど聞いて 本当の言葉を
Listen until you're drenched, to the real words
息づく鼓動を
to the breathing heartbeat.
闇に迷うのは
Losing one's way in the darkness...
一つじゃない道があるから
...is not just one because there are paths.
駆けて 求めて また傷が増えて
Running, searching, and getting hurt again
全て捨て去れば痛みなどない
If I cast everything away, there would be no pain
demo立ち尽くすだけじゃ見られない
But I can't see it if I just stand still,
明日があるの
because there is a tomorrow.
満ちていた光が
The overflowing light...
いつか訪れると思っていた
...I thought would arrive someday.
誰も同じと独りよがりしては
Thinking everyone is the same, being self-righteous,
目を逸らした
I averted my eyes.
喉につかえた言葉を飲み込んでしまった
I ended up swallowing the words stuck in my throat,
本当のことも隠して嘘吐いた
hiding the truth and telling lies.
声を殺した 心を誤魔化して
Stifling my voice, deceiving my heart,
この仮初の姿
with this transient appearance,
生きてると言えるだろうか
can I truly be called living?
だから
So,
不安の端に気づいてよ
notice the edge of my anxiety.
選べば失って 恐れては耐えて
If I choose, I lose; fearing, I endure,
枯れてしまうけど
though I will wither away.
転ぶのより傷が増えても
Even if I get more wounds than from just falling,
前に進むんじゃない
I'm moving forward, aren't I?
I beg you...
ねえ聞いて本当の言葉を
Hey, listen to my true words,
生きている鼓動を
to my living heartbeat...
どうか どうか
Please, please,
その目に映して
reflect it in those eyes of yours.
また夢を見よう
Let's dream once again.
私も怖いけど
I'm scared too, but...
君がいれば
...as long as you're here.
というわけで皆さん、こんやっぴー！
And with that, hello everyone, Konyappi~!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワです！イェーイ！
Yes! I'm Tokoyami Towa from Hololive's 4th Generation! Yay!
ということで、本日は生誕祭...
So, today is my Birthday Festival...
あ、今日はね、トワちゃんの誕生日なんです。ハッピーバースデー、えー、トワ to トワということで。
Ah, today is actually Towa-chan's birthday! Happy birthday, um, Towa, from Towa to Towa!
お誕生日と、アンドそして！
My birthday, and... and also!
アンドそして！何回言うんだよってね。
And also! How many times am I going to say that?
なんと、新衣装のお披露目もあります！イェーイ！
There is also a new outfit reveal! Yay!
100万人記念を使って、新衣装を作っていただきました！イェーイ！
We used the 1 million subscribers milestone to have this new outfit made! Yay!
そしてね、今日のライブなんですが、ミニライブになっておりまして、
And as for today's live, it's actually a mini-live,
大体30分、から40分ぐらいで終わるんじゃないかなと思ってるんですけども、
and I think it'll probably end in about 30 to 40 minutes.
その短い時間でも楽しんでいただければなと思います！お願いいします！
But even in that short time, I hope you enjoy it! Thank you!
はい、で、今回は、えっと、SUP-Sさんというね、会社にね、手伝ってもらって、
Yes! And this time, a company called Soup-s helped us
今日のライブを作てます！スープさんありがとう！
create today's live! Thank you, Soup-s!
そしてね、これ収録なんですけれど、
And, well, this is actually pre-recorded,
収録の日に、スープさんから「トワさんの生誕祭に応募したんですけど外れました」みたいな...
but on the recording day, they told me, "We applied for Towa's Birthday Festival but lost the lottery..."
ことを言われて、「えっ、知らなかったんだけど応募してたんかい！」って。
I was like, "Wait, I didn't know you guys even applied!"
もう何度も本当にお世話になってるんですけどね。ちょっとプチ笑いというか。
Even though they've always helped me so much. It was a funny little moment.
ということで、えー、今日はね、さっきも言った通り、
So, as I mentioned earlier, today
新衣装、3Dの新衣装もありますし、
we have the new 3D outfit,
他にもなんと発表がありますので、
and on top of that, there's actually an announcement!
ぜひ最後までここに居座り続けてください！
So please make sure to stay tuned until the very end!
はい、で、そしてハッシュタグのお知らせです！ピッ、こちら！
Yes, and next is the hashtag announcement! Here it is!
はい、ハッシュタグ「#常闇トワ生誕祭2026」になりますので、
The hashtag is #TokoyamiTowaBirthdayFestival2026,
ぜひたくさん感想をポストしてくださいね。
so please post lots of your thoughts!
えー、美人の写真のスクリーンショットも待っておりますよ。はい。はい。
I'm also looking forward to screenshots of my beautiful self! Yes, yes.
で、えっと、曲の振り返りなんですが、
Now, to look back at the songs,
1曲目が「サキガケ」をファーストソロライブ、
for the first song "Sakigake",
ファーストソロライブの衣装を着て歌わせていただきました。
I performed it wearing my first solo live outfit.
え、そして2曲目はですね、不可視を、
And for the second song "Fukashi",
セカンドソロライブの衣装で歌わせていただきました！イェーイ！
I sang it in my second solo live outfit! Yay!
あの、そこまで意図してなかったんだけど、
I didn't actually plan it that way,
どちらの曲もね、ソロライブの、1番本当に最後の最後の、
but both songs were the absolute final encore songs
アンコールの最後の曲だったんですよ。
of my respective solo lives.
もう、どっちもね、好きだから入れただけなんですけど。はい。
I just included them because I love both of them, though. Yes.
なんか、この収録をしてるときに、
Somehow, while doing this recording,
どっちのソロライブの景色がね、思い浮かんでちょっとエモかったです。はい。
the sights from both solo lives came to mind, and I got emotional. Yes.
ぜひブルーレイも発売してるのでチェックしてくださいね。
The Blu-rays are also available, so please check them out!
はい、そして次なんですけれども、
Yes! And next up,
えー、なんと、先日ソロライブを終えた、
my goodness, she just finished her solo live recently...
あの、超超超超超超大物ゲストと一緒に歌っちゃいます！
I'll be singing with that super, super, super major guest!
えー、こちら、えー、ま、もう言っちゃうと、
Well, to just say it already,
ねねちが、ねねち？ねねねが来てくれます！
Nenechi... Nenechi? Nene-ne is joining me!
ねねねとね、えー、先日6月28日に、なんと...
Nene-ne and I, on June 28th, actually...
もうこれなんか、もう受け入れてる形にはなってるんだけど、
Well, I've pretty much accepted it by now, but
ねねトワはカップル4周年記念...
NeneTowa celebrated our 4th anniversary of being a couple...
ねねトワ、カップル？ね、ねねトワは...
NeneTowa, a couple? Yes, NeneTowa...
4周年記念になりまして、そこで初めて、オリ曲を出したんですよ。
celebrated our 4th anniversary, and we released our first original song!
その曲をね、今日は、なんとフルバージョンでお届けしたいと思います！
And today, we'd like to perform that song in its full version!
「#ウチらしか勝たん」どうぞ！
Please enjoy "#Uchira Shika Katan"!
#ウチらしか勝たん
作詞・作曲：knoak
#Uchira Shika Katan
Lyrics & Composition: knoak
盛れてる角度で切り取る今日
Framing today from our best angles,
って、でもそれだけじゃ物足りないでしょ
but that alone isn't enough, right?
Do you know why? Seek a must punch in your life.
賞賛喝采もっと頂戴 ハイハイ こちらに注目
Give me more praise and applause! Yes, yes, pay attention here!
キュートなだけじゃ終われない
I can't just end with being cute.
でも少し苦い甘いスパイス
But a slightly bitter, sweet spice.
私をポップスター
Make me a pop star,
画面越しのサイン
a sign through the screen.
そう簡単には触れさせはしないの
I won't let you touch me that easily.
ねえ こっちに来たいんでしょ？
Hey, you want to come over here, right?
隣にいてほしいんでしょ？
You want me by your side, right?
ねえ もっと見たいんでしょ？
Hey, you want to see more, right?
私が欲しいんでしょ？
You want me, right?
完全優勝でしょ
It's a complete victory, right?
まだまだ足りない 私へのLike
Still not enough "Likes" for me!
単純明快な世界
A simple and clear world...
いや まだ足りない 脳内足りない
No, it's still not enough, not enough in my brain!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん 私しか勝たん
Win, win, win, only I can win!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん ウチラしか勝たん
Win, win, win, only we can win!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん 私しか勝たん
Win, win, win, only I can win!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん ウチラしか勝たん
Win, win, win, only we can win!
おどけるライトで塗り替える今日
Painting over today with playful lights,
でも綺麗なだけじゃ Oh no no
but just being beautiful is a no-no.
つまんないでしょ 想像以上のショー
That's boring, right? A show beyond imagination!
期待以上を見せてほしいの
I want you to show me more than I expect.
ねえ もっと近づきたいんでしょ？
Hey, you want to get closer, right?
本音だって知りたいんでしょ？
You want to know my real feelings too, right?
ねえ 目を合わせたいんでしょ？
Hey, you want to make eye contact, right?
私しかいないんでしょ？
There's only me, right?
断然本命でしょ
Definite favorite, right?
まだまだ足りない 私へのLike
Still not enough "Likes" for me!
絶対運命でしょ
It must be fate, right?
いや まだ足りない 愛足りない
No, it's still not enough, not enough love.
その目の奥見つめたいの
I want to look deep into your eyes,
その熱ごと欲しくなるの
I want to have all of that passion.
正論なんていらないの
I don't need any logical arguments,
ねえ 本音を聞かせて
hey, let me hear your true feelings.
完全優勝でしょ
It's a complete victory, right?
まだまだ足りない 私へのLike
Still not enough "Likes" for me!
絶対運命でしょ
It must be fate, right?
いや まだ足りない 愛足りない
No, it's still not enough, not enough love.
全然足りない 脳内足りない
Not enough at all, not enough in my brain!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん 私しか勝たん
Win, win, win, only I can win!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん ウチラしか勝たん
Win, win, win, only we can win!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん 私しか勝たん
Win, win, win, only I can win!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん ウチラしか勝たん
Win, win, win, only we can win!
はい！ということで、えー、ねねトワで『ウチラしか勝たん』でしたー！
Yes! And so, that was NeneTowa with "Only We Can Win"!
どうだったでしょうか？ダンス、頑張りました。ねね、ありがとう！
How did you like it? We worked hard on the dance. Nene, thank you!
はい、ちょっとギャルっぽい感じで振り付けもね、えー、アイリ先生に作ってもらいました！
Yes, we had Airi-sensei make a slightly gyaru-style choreography for us!
もうトワね、勝たん勝たんが結構好きで、このピースのところ、勝たん勝たん勝たん。
Towa really likes the "Katan, katan" part, especially this peace sign section, "katan, katan, katan".
これがね、ギャルっぽくて可愛くて、すごいい好きです。
This part is so gyaru-like and cute, I love it.
ぜひ踊ってみてね！
Please try dancing to it!
『踊ってみてね』むずいな。
Saying "try dancing to it" is actually hard.
はい、ぜひね、あの、いっぱい繰り返し、えー、見てもらえればなと思います。聴いてね、曲も！
Yes, please watch it over and over again. Listen to the song too!
はーい。
Alright.
ということで、えー、お待たせいたしました。
So, thank you for waiting.
この後は、
Next up,
常闇トワちゃん、新、新、
Tokoyami Towa's... new... new...
3D、あ、違う、3D新衣装の発表！
3D... ah, wait, new 3D outfit reveal!
ということで、着替えていきたいと思います。
So, I'm going to go change into it now.
着替えます。
I'll change now.
あ、じゃ、着替えますからね、着替えますからね。
Ah, alright, I'm changing now, okay? I'm going to change!
うんと、うんしょ、うんしょと。
Ugh, struggle, struggle...
はー、大変だ。
Phew, this is tough.
すごい、やっぱり、しょ、うん、ううお！
Wow, as expected... oh, ugh!
どんなんだよ、ということで、えー、着替えました。
What kind of sound was that? Anyway, I've changed!
では、いいですか？行きますよ、皆さん。
Now, are you ready? Here we go, everyone!
行きますよ、なんか、ザーボンさん、ドドリアさん、来た。
Here we go... Wait, Zarbon and Dodoria have arrived?
あ、あ、やばい、美しい足が、美しい足が、
Oh, oh, look! The beautiful legs... the beautiful legs...
出ております。あ、バランスが取りづらい。
Are showing! Ah, it's hard to keep my balance.
どう？ほら、まず、この足！
How is it? Look at these legs first!
この、なんか、最近のさ、流行りなよ。この薄々の靴下、これ名前なんていうのかわかんないけど。
These are like... super trendy lately! These sheer socks, though I don't know what they're called.
衣装をね、さっき、ひろ先生に描いていただいたんですけども、
This outfit was designed by Hiro-sensei,
先生のね、あの、センスが良すぎて、私にはこの名前が何なのかというのはわからないんですが、
but sensei's taste is so incredibly good that I don't even know what these are called...
でも、こんな感じの足になってますよ。
But this is what the legs look like!
イラストレーターの皆さん、必見でございます！
All you illustrators out there, this is a must-see!
で、持って、リボンも可愛くない？ほら！
And look, aren't the ribbons cute too? Look!
あ、いいですね、カメラさん。いいですね。
Ah, nice angle, camera-san! Very nice.
ほらほら！
Look, look!
はい、じゃ、だんだん上に上がって。
Okay, let's slowly pan up.
ズーム...
Zoom in...
ちょっとスカートの、あ、やばい。スカートって言っちゃった。あ、スカートじゃない。
Just to the skirt... Oh, wait, I said skirt. No, it's not a skirt.
のところまで。
...to that part.
ストップ！
Stop!
はい。スカート、こんな感じになってます。
Yes. The skirt looks like this.
スカートというか、これなんていうか、一応ズボンなんですよね。
Or rather than a skirt, what should I call this? It's actually pants.
はい。で、見て。
Yes, and look!
可愛くない？
Isn't it cute?
ビビのキーホルダーだ！もにょもにょもにょ...
It's a Bibi keychain! *wiggle wiggle wiggle*
可愛い。
Cute.
もにょもにょもにょ...
*wiggle wiggle wiggle*
はい、キーホルダーがついてたりとか、
Yes, there's a keychain attached,
ちゃんと尻尾が出るようになってたりとかしております。
and my tail comes out properly like this.
させて見てください。
And please look at this.
ネイルと指輪！
My nails and rings!
アクセサリー。ほら、こんな感じです。
Accessories. Look, they're like this.
きん、ちょっとギャルで可愛いでしょ？
They look a bit like a gal's, pretty cute, right?
いぇーい。
Yeah!
はい。で、これで多分みんなスクリーンショットしたから、
Yes, and now that everyone has probably taken screenshots,
ネイルま、意外とトワのネイル真似する人いっぱいいるんですよ。だから、
a lot of people actually copy Towa's nail art. So,
このネイルを多分真似してくれるでしょう。
they'll probably copy these nails too.
はい、ということで、ちょっと見えてきちゃってますけれども、ちょっと首のところまで。
Alright, so, you can already see it a bit, but let's go up to the neck.
じゃあ、上げて、上げて。
Now, go up, go up...
ど、うわ！やばい！髪の毛が...
Wha- Whoa! Oh no, my hair is...
え、なんか長くない？ちょっと髪の毛長くない？
Wait, isn't it kind of long? Isn't my hair a bit long?
ちょっとおばさんみたいな言い方になってる。
Now I sound like an old lady.
はい、で、これがジャケットですね。ジャケットに、
Yes, so this is the jacket. Over the jacket,
ちょっと透け感があるトップスに、ということで、
a slightly sheer top. So,
はい、腕には
yes, on my arm,
「TOWA」と、「常闇トワ」と書いてあります。
it says 'TOWA', 'Tokoyami Towa'.
こっちは何にもない。
Nothing on this side.
はい、ちょっと後ろ見ちゃうと、あっ、
Yes, if we look at the back... ah!
なんかストレートじゃない？髪の毛が。
Isn't my hair kind of straight?
ということで、上まで行っちゃいますか。
Alright, let's go all the way up!
はい、ドン！
Ready, bam!
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
ということで、帽子もついてたりして、
And so, with a hat and everything,
こんな感じです。いぇーい。
it looks like this. Yay!
はい、どうでしょう？
Yes, how is it?
はい、今、撮るところですよ。はい、
Yes, now is the time to take pictures. Yes,
撮るところですよ。いぇーい。
now is the time to take pictures. Yay!
はい。
Yes.
そう、今回キャップ。キャップなんです。
Yes, a cap this time. It's a cap.
ちょっとストリート系というか、なんていうか。
It's a bit like street style, or something like that.
でしょう？で、あとは、
Right? And also,
こっちだ。
this side.
ギャルっぽい
It's a gal-style...
キラキラついてます！これもセンスが高すぎて
...sparkly thing! This is also so stylish,
よくわかってないけど、ついてるやつ。
I don't really get it, but it's there.
最悪だよ。自分についてんのに。
That's terrible, considering it's on me.
センスが凄すぎるんですよね、いつも。
The design sense is always amazing.
あの、デザインしてもらうと、びっくりします。お洒落すぎて。
When they design for me, I'm always surprised because it's so fashionable.
であと、ちょっとカッコよ目のパールと
And then, these slightly cool pearls
チェーンのネックレスをつけたりとかしております。
and chain necklace are also on me.
裏はこんな感じ。
The back is like this.
おっ？
Oh?
はい。
Yes.
では、
Now then,
なんと、
surprisingly,
この帽子、取れちゃうんです！
this hat can be taken off!
ちょっと帽子取ってきますね。
Let me go take off the hat.
よいしょ。
Oof.
うおー、ふぅ。
Ugh, phew.
取れました。帽子。
I've taken it off. The hat.
すごいでしょ？
Amazing, right?
もう、日差しを直接受けてしまいます。というのは置いといて、
Now, I'll be getting direct sunlight. But putting that aside,
はい。白いね、メッシュがついてたりとか、
yes, there's some white mesh details,
このキラキラしてるのがついてたりとか、あと、
this sparkly stuff is attached, and also,
今回はハーフ、ハーフアップというか、ハーフアップではないけど、これ三つ編みで
this time it's a half... half-up? It's not a half-up, but it's braided...
編み込みしてもらって、後ろ、
...braided in, and at the back,
可愛く結んでます。こんな感じです。
it's tied up cute. It looks like this.
こんな感じです。
Like this.
これ、ちゃんとね、イラストレーターさんのみなが
I want the illustrators to draw this,
ファート書いてくれるのを楽しみにしてるんで、ゆっくり見せてます。
so I'm showing it slowly. I'm looking forward to your art!
あとは、もういつも通りピアスがばちばちついてたりしてます。
And also, my piercings are flashy as usual.
はい。で、今、
Yes. And now,
ちょっとまだジャケット着てるんですけれども、このジャケットを脱ぐと、
I'm still wearing the jacket, but if I take it off...
あ、脱ぐことができるんですよ。脱ぐとどうなるか見せたいと思います。
Oh, I can take it off. I'll show you what it looks like without it.
脱ぐ、うわー！
Off... Whoa!
この、この名残惜しく出るのにハマってるのかもしれない。
I might be obsessed with leaving the frame reluctantly like this.
うわー！
Whaaa!
えー、この叫び声。あ、こんな感じです。
Um, that scream. Oh, it looks like this!
この、20キロあるジャケットを脱ぎました。あ、帽子は30キロありました。
I took off this 20 kg jacket. To me, the hat was 30 kg.
すごい今首が軽いです。ということで、
My neck feels so light now. So,
こんな感じ！
it's like this!
この、トワがわーわー言ってる間ね、スタジオはすっごいシーンとしてるから、すっごい恥ずかしいんだよ。
While Towa is shouting like this, the studio is dead silent, so it's super embarrassing!
はい、見てください。
Yes, look at this.
と
And...
いぇーい。あ、わかった。
Yay! Oh, I know!
これや。まず。はい。
Let's do this first. Ready?
これで写真撮ってて、みんな。
Everyone, take a picture of this.
はい。
Ready...
Ｔ。あ、Ｔじゃない。これ言っちゃだめだ、これ。Ｐ、はい。
T... Ah, not T. I shouldn't say that. P! Okay.
こんな感じです。いぇーい。
It looks like this! Yay!
後ろも。
From the back, too.
はい。こんな感じ。すっきりするよね。ジャケットないだけで。
Here it is. It looks much sleeker without the jacket, right?
はい。で、まだ、さらにあるんです。
Yes. And there's actually even more.
実は、この
Actually, this...
上、黒のトップス
black top up here...
色変わるんです。虹色に。
...can change color! Into rainbow!
ちょっと待ってください。
Please wait a moment.
ええと、塗り替えてと。
Okay, let me repaint it...
でもう終わったから。
And since it's done now...
うわ、出てきた。はい。
Whoa, here I am. Okay!
じゃじゃーん！虹色ではないです。白です！
Tada! It's not rainbow, it's white!
だから、上と下、白白にすることができるんですよね。
So I can wear white both on top and on the bottom!
はい。どうでしょう。
Yes. What do you think?
で、まだね、いく、他にも実は組み合わせがあるんで
And actually, there are other combinations as well,
どの組み合わせが良かったのか、後で教えてください。
so please tell me later which combination you liked best.
はい、で、あ、これスクショしてくださいね。はい、はいスクショタイム。
Okay, and oh, please screenshot this. Okay, screenshot time!
この時点で何をしたいのか分かった人、静かにですよ。
If you already know what I'm trying to do here, keep it a secret!
はい。では、そしてなんと、
Okay, now, and surprisingly...
下もね、実は変わるんですよ。
the bottom actually changes, too!
シュールすぎる。たまりは反対側変えろよみたいな感じだけど、はい。
This is too surreal. It's like, "Hurry up and change the other side already." Okay.
じゃじゃじゃじゃーん、じゃーん、黒色！
Tada-da-da! Tada, it's black!
じゃーん。こっちが白で、こっちが黒。どうでしょう。
Tada! White on top, black on the bottom. What do you think?
最初とは違う色になってますけれども、ま、白黒でもね、かっこいい感じ、シンプルだけどかっこいいみたいな感じで
It's a different color than the first one. Even monochrome is cool and simple but stylish.
色違いも作ってもらいました！いぇーい！
So we had them make color variations! Yay!
あれ、スクショタイムだよね。
Oh, it's screenshot time, right?
さっきこう、こうできたから、こう。
Since we did this and this earlier, now... this.
え、こう？こう？
Wait, like this? Or this?
ダサすぎる。
That looks so uncool!
まあ、なんかいいようにしてください。いぇーい。
Well, just make it look good somehow. Yay!
ちゃん、
Yeah!
そんな感じでね。え、ということでだから、上が白黒、下も白黒ということでね、上と下でね、え、白黒白黒でね、好きな組み合わせにできる衣装になっております。ありがとう！
And that's how it is. So, both the top and bottom come in white and black, allowing you to mix and match them however you like! Thank you!
はい。ではじゃあ、最初の服に戻るかな。少々お待ちください。
Okay. Now, let's change back to the first outfit. Please wait a moment.
シュシュシュシュ。ふう、この３０キロの帽子と２０キロのジャケットを着て、うっ。
(Whoosh sounds) Whew, putting on this 30 kg hat and 20 kg jacket... ugh...
で、服も塗り替えてまた、ペンキベタベタで戻ってきて、ふう。
...and repainting the clothes... returning covered in wet paint... whew.
はい。ということで、最後。あ、ちょっと待って、最後ね。はい、これ。
All right! So, the last pose. Ah, wait, for the last one... here it is.
最後、こ、こうか。こうじゃない。こう？
For the last one, is it... like this? No, not like this. Like this?
こう？まあ、いいようにしてください。はい。
This? Well, just make it look good. Yes.
ということでいっぱい、各、色違いにスクリーンショットゾーンを撮ったんですけど。どうでしたか？
So we took screenshots of each color variation. How was it?
ＴＯＷＡという文字を作りました。ぜひ、ぜひ、どうぞ。
I made the letters T-O-W-A! Please, feel free to use them.
何を、何をどうぞって感じなんだけど、まあ、ということでこんな感じで新衣装はこういう風になっております。いぇーい。いっぱいね、ハッシュタグとか、ね、いっぱい書いてくれたら嬉しいです。いつもありがとうございます。
I don't really know what "feel free to use" even means, but anyway, that's what the new outfit looks like! Yay! I'd be happy if you post lots of thoughts with the hashtag. Thank you as always!
ということで、この後は嬉しいお知らせとなります。
So, up next, we have some exciting news!
常闇トワ誕生日記念２０２６のグッズを発売決定ー！いぇーい！
Tokoyami Towa's Birthday Celebration 2026 merchandise is officially going on sale! Yay!
こちらの配信後に、発売開始となりますので、概要欄をチェックして待ってててくだいさいね。ということで、
They will be on sale right after this stream, so please check the description box and wait. So,
気になるグッズの詳細はこちらをご覧ください。どうぞ！
here are the details of the merchandise. Have a look!
わああ！うわああ！
Whoa! Whoaaa!
うっ、ういしょっと。え、ということで、えー、
Ugh... there we go. So...
イラストは、美和先生に描き下ろしていただきました。いぇーい！
...the illustration was drawn by Miwa-sensei! Yay!
可愛いでしょ、これ。
Isn't this so cute?
え、旅行、お出かけをイメージして描いてもらい、今回の新衣装を、えー、モチーフとして、モチーフというか、新衣装で描てもらいました。
It was drawn with a travel/outing theme, featuring my new outfit as the motif, or rather, wearing my new outfit.
そしてね、灯籠祭りや、えー、ランタン祭り大好きなので、そちらをモチーフにしてもらってます。
Also, I love lantern festivals, so that is featured as a motif, too.
よし、ということで、こっから立ってね。ういしょっと。はあ。お待たせいたしました。はい。
All right, let me stand up from here... up we go. Whew. Thank you for waiting! Yes.
ということで、この後、というか、１つずつ
So, after this... I mean, let's look at them one by one.
アイテムを紹介していきたいと思います！
I'd like to introduce the merchandise!
まずはこちら、どうぞ、ドン！
First up is this! Here we go!
「願いを込めて」LEDアートパネル！イェーイ！
The "With a Wish" LED Art Panel! Yay!
このね、あのMYAO先生に描き下ろしてもらったイラストを使って、
Using this illustration drawn specially by MYAO-sensei...
えー、アートパネルを作っちゃいました！なんとこのアートパネル、
...we made an art panel! And guess what, this art panel...
LEDが入っておりますので、ふんわり光っちゃいます！
...has LEDs built-in, so it glows softly!
ちょっと美しい感じでしょ？ぜひこの際に手に入れてくださいね。
It has a beautiful feel, doesn't it? Make sure to get one!
はい。
Yes.
そして、２つ目はこちら、ボン！
And the second item is this, boom!
「どっちのトワにする？」リバーシブルアクリルスタンド！
The "Which Towa will you choose?" Reversible Acrylic Stand!
はい、え、こちらはですね、この新衣装の、え、撮り下ろしとなっておりまして、
Yes, this is a newly taken shot of me in this new outfit.
さっき色々帽子つけたりとか、上が黒だったり下が黒だったり上が白だったり下が白だったりみたいな色々色違いを見せたと思うんですけど、
I showed you various color variations earlier, like wearing a hat, black top or bottom, white top or bottom...
それをね、ちゃんと表現してるアクリルスタンドになっております。え、表のトワちゃん、え、裏のトワちゃん、
...and this acrylic stand perfectly represents that! Front Towa, back Towa...
どっちのトワにするの？
...which Towa will you choose?
ということで、こちらも手に入れてくださいね。
So, please get this one as well!
はい、え、続いてはこちら！
Yes, and next up is this!
新衣装モチーフキーホルダー！
The New Outfit Motif Keychain!
見てください、これです、これ。
Look at this, this one right here.
この、トワのビビと、おらおらおら、TOWAと書いたこのキーホルダーが、
This keychain of Towa's Bibi and the letters "TOWA"...
このキーホルダーが、ここのアクセサリーがキーホルダーになっちゃいます！イェーイ！
...the accessory here has turned into a keychain! Yay!
はい、え、このね、モチーフにしてますので、ぜひお揃いで手に入れてみてください。
Yes, since it's a motif, please get one to match me!
パーツはね、それぞれ取り外し可能になっております。よろしくお願いいたします。
Each part can be detached separately. Thank you!
はい、そして最後はこちら、ドーン！
And finally, this one, boom!
トワとお揃いキャップ！イェーイ！
The Towa Matching Cap! Yay!
このね、帽子とお揃いのキャップを発売することになりました！
We're releasing a cap that matches this hat!
普段使いしやすいデザインにもなってますので、ぜひ、今日トワとお揃いの帽子をつけたいなっていう方は購入してみてください。お願いします。
It's designed for everyday use, so if you want to wear the same cap as Towa, please buy it!
はい、ということで、こんな感じかな？紹介は。
Yes, so that's about it for the merchandise, right?
あ、そうだった！戻る前に、
Oh, that's right! Before I go back...
この全部を買ったフルセット特典、あ、フルセット購入特典もあります！
There's also a bonus for purchasing the full set with all these items!
忘れておりました。
I almost forgot about it.
え、フルセットをご購入いただいた皆さんには、え、箔押し複製サインと、
For everyone who purchases the full set, you'll receive a foil-stamped duplicated signature...
あと今回は、メッセージ入りポストカードをプレゼントしたいと思います！ぜひ、フルセットで購入してみてください。
...and a postcard with a handwritten message! Please consider buying the full set.
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Yes, thank you very much!
はい、で、ここから、あ、そうだ。ここからまだここにいて、
Yes, and from here... Oh right, staying right here...
なんとこれだけじゃないんですよ。グッズだけじゃなくて、あ、グッズは概要欄もチェックしてほしいのと、あと、
...that's not all! Not only merchandise—by the way, check the description box for the merch—but also...
そうなんです、最初のね、配信の最初に言ったと思うんですけれども、
Yes, as I mentioned at the very beginning of the stream...
お知らせがまだ一個あるんですよ。
...there is still one more announcement!
はい。そのお知らせとは、こちら、ボーン！
Yes, and that announcement is this, boom!
新曲「SMASH IT UP」が、この後２４時から、え、０時になった瞬間からデジタルリリースされます！
My new song "SMASH IT UP" will be digitally released starting at midnight tonight!
え、いつもね、あのトワの楽曲とか作る時にすごいお世話になってる、え、いそのさんという方がいらっしゃるんですけど、いそのさんにね、書き下ろしていただきました。
It was written by Isono-san, who always helps me a lot when making my songs.
なんか、その、結構ざっくり「トワっぽい曲でお願いします」って、トワっぽいとの、結構お世話になってるんですよ。
I vaguely asked him, "Please make a Towa-like song." He knows my style very well.
だから、トワの音域とか、どういうのが得意かっていうのもすごい知ってくださってるので、じゃあ、そのなんか最大限に活かしたようなトワの曲を作ってくださいって言って、できた曲が「SMASH IT UP」なんですよね。
He knows my vocal range and strengths, so I asked him to make a song that maximizes them, resulting in "SMASH IT UP"!
うん。結構ね、なんか、でも来た時は、
Yes, though when I first heard it...
「トワ、トワ歌えるかな、トワっぽいかな？え、でもこういうイメージ抱いてるんだな」っていう風な感じで、すごい面白かったです。
I thought, "Can I sing this? Is it like me? Ah, so this is his image of me." It was very interesting!
なんでね、え、でもね、その不安だったんですよ、最初撮るまでは。
I was actually a bit anxious before we recorded it.
でも撮ってみたらすごい自分に合ってて、かっこいい曲になったので、ぜひ、あの購入して聞いていただければなと思いました。ダウンロードしてみてください！
But once we recorded it, it fit me perfectly and became a really cool song. Please download and listen to it!
はい、じゃあね、
Well then...
「どんな曲なんだよ」って、「そんなの、ゼロでダウンロードなんてできないよ」って思うじゃないですか。
You might be thinking, "What kind of song is it?" or "I can't just download it blindly."
いやいや、今日はその、この発表した新曲で、本日のライブを締めくくりたいと...
No, no. Today, with this new song, I would like to close out today's concert...
え、ここカットして、
Wait, cut this part out...
ここカットしてって言ったけど、カットしなくていいですからね。
I said "cut this out" but you don't actually have to cut it.
はい、ではそんな新曲で、本日のライブを締めくくりたいと思います！
Alright, with that new song, I'd like to close today's concert!
いいですか？
Are you ready?
では、本日最後の曲です。
Now, here is the final song of today.
聞いてください！SMASH IT UP!
Please listen! SMASH IT UP!
熱に当てられ
Driven by the heat,
熱を与えて
giving off heat...
シンクロしていく is her core
Synchronizing, is her core.
くだらないボーダー SMASH IT UP!
Smash this worthless border! SMASH IT UP!
溶けるように 交じり合っていく
As if melting, they blend together...
本能と理性
Instinct and reason.
始めよう 再構築
Let's begin the reconstruction!
スポットライト頂戴
Give me the spotlight.
プロットはいらない
No plot is needed.
根拠なら目の前に
The proof is right in front of us.
ひとり残らず巻き込むライオット
A riot dragging in every single person.
貫く覚悟 限界玉砕しちゃうわ
Ready to go all the way, I'll smash through my limits.
歴史は消せない過去を記す
History records an unerasable past.
歌う繊細豪快 自在に
Singing delicately yet dynamically, at will,
世界が無視できないくらい
so much that the world cannot ignore us.
暗い...
Dark...
影をとっては捨て
taking and throwing away the shadows,
強くあれ
remain strong!
前乗りのBPM 狂気じみたプライド 裂いて
Fast-paced BPM, tearing apart a madness-tinged pride.
くだらないボーダー SMASH IT UP!
Smash this worthless border! SMASH IT UP!
凝り固まった価値観 壊せ 壊せ 壊せ 壊せ
Break, break, break, break the rigid values!
絵空事だって確か 作る 作る 作る
Even if it's a pipe dream, I'll surely make it reality!
ブレンドして 真実
Blend it into truth...
揺れ動いちゃう心境も 手懐け
taming even my wavering feelings.
堂々大シンフォニー
A grand, majestic symphony,